Vitor Miranda

Web Developer

Personal Info

Address

323 Colborne Street, London-ON, N6B3N8

Phone

+1 (647) 937-9470

E-mail

vcmiranda@outlook.com

www

https://www.vcmiranda.me

Github

https://github.com/vcmiranda

LinkedIn

https://ca.linkedin.com/in/vcmiranda

Projects

- https://tournkey.app Sports event management system
- https://www.yipstour.com Golf tournament advertisement
- Dollarama Management Web System (internal)
- Dollarcity Management WebSystem (internal)
- Info Management App Allow information and image update for Dollarama Apps (internal)

Skills

- Front end development HTML, CSS
 (Bootstrap), Javascript, JQuery
- Front end framework AngularJS, React, Vue.js
- Back end development Node.js, Express.js, Knex.js
- Database PostgreSQL, MySQL,
 MSSQL, Oracle
- Tools Gulp, JSON, Webpack, REST
- Design Tools Adobe Photoshop,
 Adobe Illustrator
- Software Version Control Git,
 Github, Gitlab
- Server Linux, Windows

Hard-working Web Developer specialized in JavaScript having professional experience working with AngularJS, React, and Vue, with a flair for developing structured APIs and creating elegant websites and web applications in the least amount of time. Solid project management background, being responsible or having participated of the deployment of solutions in a variety of domains. Provided in-company training to more than 1000 people in project management software. Responsible for growth and mentoring of other team members (developing intern technical and management skills).

Experience

2019-01 - Web Developer

present

binnj, inc. - London, ON

- Develop and improve web applications using AngularJS and its ecosystem.
- Design and develop Single Page Applications (SPA) using React, React-Router and Redux from scratch.
- Develop Electron app using React.
- Implement responsive web UI and improve UX using SASS and Bootstrap.
- Consume REST web service to get needed data.
- Create web maps using Google Maps and Google APIs
- Manage source code using Git and Gitlab.

2017-05 - Full Stack Web Developer

2018-12

Sport-Travel - London, ON

- Create RESTful API endpoints using NodeJS and ExpressJS
- Develop web/mobile app to consume the API using VueJS/HTML5/CSS
- Write many unit tests, api tests
- Handle CRUD using Knex,js, and MySQL / PostgreSQL
- Implement payment system using Stripe
- Control source code and administer project issues using Git and Github
- Conduct project using Trello Agile methodology
- Work with clients to establish system requirements and design

2017-01 - **Peer Tutor**

2018-01

Fanshawe College - London, ON

• Supported academic development of other students by assisting in the understanding of concepts in Programming (Javascript, PHP), Network, Database (MSSQL, Oracle), and Web Design (Photoshop, HTML, CSS), improving their grades in 25% average.

2012-08 -

Project Management Consultant/Instructor

2016-03

Prosperi Tecnology - Vitoria, BR

- Conducted software projects, handling all the aspects of management, development, and deployment using Microsoft PPM Solution (Sharepoint, Project Server/Project Online, Project, and BI Solutions SSRS, SSAS, Power BI), generating around \$160,000 in revenue.
- Administered project risks, issue and constraints, reducing change requests in 33% of the projects
- Provided training for over a 1000 people in project management software
- Developed custom training material according to the client's needs

2014-03 - College Professor

2016-02

UCL – Centro Leste College - Serra, BR

- Taught planning using project management software to more than 200 students
- Provided relevant assignments for students that demonstrate learning outcomes in a real-life setting
- Facilitated access of project management tools and training materials

- Web Hosting Solutions Google Cloud, Microsoft Azure
- Microsoft Project Management MSProject, MS Project Online, MSProject Server

2015-01 - Coordinator

2016-01 Microsoft Innovation Center - Vitoria, BR

- Provided open training in IT to the community, focused on the development of more than 100 students in Microsoft technology (Infrastructure and software development)
- Managed team of 4 students/developers that developed Windows apps, according to Microsoft requirements
- Provided free lectures related to Microsoft technology and presented by Microsoft evangelists to the community

2011-04 - Planning and PMO Analyst

2012-08

Concremat Engineering and Technology Inc - Vitoria, BR

- Improved, with PMO team, a project management methodology based on market best practices, reducing project time in 15%, and budget in 12%
- Directed team responsible for building processes workflow of an engineering department
- Developed a process to improve quality of schedules that has been built by planners, reducing rework in 32%
- Provided training in project management to a team of more 15 engineers
- Followed and managed risks in more than 20 projects at the same time
- Executed supplier evaluation process, improving deliverable quality in 24%

Education

2016-09 -	Fanshawe College - London, ON
2018-04	Internet Application and Web Development
2007-03 -	UVV – Vila Velha University - Vitoria, Brazil
2008-12	MBA in Project Management
2001-08 -	UVV – Vila Velha University - Vitoria, Brazil
2006-12	Bachelor in Business Administration

Certificates

2013	MS Managing Project with Microsoft Project 2013
2013	MS Managing Project and Portfolios with Project Server 2013
2013	MCSE Core Solutions of Microsoft Sharepoint Server 2013
2012	MCTS Microsoft Project 2010, Managing Projects